Jumoke Adekanmi

Senior Web Developer 212-363-0754 ◆ JumokeA@gmail.com ◆ Odenton, MD

SUMMARY:

I am an analytical and innovative Software Developer with over 12 years' experience in web applications development. I am developing solutions for government, science, healthcare, finance, law, and community and e commerce. I deliver standards-compliant, optimized, accessible (508), responsive and adaptive cross-platform applications. I have an extensive experience with a myriad of CMS frameworks and a specialty in Drupal. I have led development, design, API integrations, migration and deployments of several large-scale websites including FTC.gov, Healthdata.gov, AOC.gov, USBG.gov, TheMIX.org, USPTO.gov, Teradata, Blue Cross Blue Shield (BCBS) and Congress member multisites' platform.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Computer Languages / Libraries & Scripts:	PHP, Python, C#, XML/JSON, YAML, HTML/CSS/Twig, Sass, Gulp, Composer, JavaScript/jQuery, ReactJS, Node, Perl, QueryPath, JSONPath, Drush, Bash Scripting, PowerShell
Databases:	MySQL/MariaDB, MSSQL, NoSQL, CouchDB, Sybase
CMS:	Drupal 7, 8, 9 & 10, WordPress 4, 5, 6, Magento, Joomla, Apigee, Salesforce, Moodle, SharePoint, DotNetNuke, Documentum
Platforms, et. al.:	Open Shift Container Platform, Linux/Ubuntu, Apache/Nginx, AWS - Lambda, Docker & Kubernetes, Acquia, Apache Solr, CDNs (Akamai and Comcast), Solr Search, Open Search.
Local Dev Boxes:	Docker, Lando, DrupalVM, Vagrant/Virtual Boxes, DDEV, Acquia Dev Desktop
Testing:	Playwright, Selenium, Behat, PHP Unit Testing
Versioning:	GIT, SVN, SourceSafe Repository Hosting: Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket
Ticketing:	Jira, Clickup, Azure DevOps Board, Trac, Rally, Bugzilla, ScrumDo, Trello, SharePoint, VSO, Redmine, Github Issues
Applications/Tools:	VSCode, PHPStorm, Eclipse, Postman, Insomnia, Swagger UI, Tableau, Site Improve, Adobe Creative Suite, Splunk, Dynatrace, Jenkins, Automation w/ Ansible
Drupal Modules / Libraries Used:	Views, Paragraphs, Layout Builder, Panels, Context, Search API, Services, JSONAPI, Migrate API, Drupal Plugins, SimpleSAMLphp, etc.
Theming tools:	Sub-themed with Bootstrap, Radix, Zen, Omega, AdaptiveTheme, USWDS.
Al-assisted tools:	GitHub Copilot, Gemini

PROFESSIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

Led migration of several websites to Drupal 7, 8, 9 and 10 and Wordpress 4, 5,6

Presented site building best practices at several Drupal meetups

2017 & 2019 Creative Excellence Nomination for WebMD's You Can Do It application

Built enterprise applications for several large scale organizations

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Ampcus Inc, Odenton, MD Lead Developer/Architect

October 2021 - Present

Currently leading strategic initiative and implementing CMS applications and API integrations using Drupal, Wordpress and Magento. I am translating non-technical business requirements into dynamic, functional web applications. I am involved in the entire SDLC: developing functional specifications, architecting appropriate solutions, driving development, overseeing deployment, and ensuring the highest quality code, testing, training and usage experience. I am involved in identifying technical solutions for issues and evolving business requirements. I help ensure objectives are met in accordance with established priorities, time limitations and funding criteria. I often write technical reports and documentation.

Ampcus Inc (and Several Contract Vehicles), Washington, DC Senior Web Developer

Jan 2017 – October 2021

Served as a Senior Developer on migration and development of a multi-site platform at US Congress. Implemented SSO, Swagger & Apigee-Integrated API Portal at USCIS (a Division of DHS). Served as hands-on Contract Lead Developer at Department of Commerce's (commerce.gov & USPTO.gov), BCBS's migration to Drupal 10. I have been performing new platform development, enhancements, integration, frontend theming, migration and full stack development of several Drupal sites. Sometimes performing DevOps which includes managing server environments, conducting deployments, deploying config changes to CDN, code-reviews, and standardizing Drupal practice and architecture.

Microfinance Information Exchange (MIX), Washington, DC Web Development Manager (Lead Drupal Developer & Architect)

Oct 2014 - Dec 2016

Served as Architect, Lead Drupal Developer and Web Technologies Manager at MIX. Performed several Drupal site migrations from Drupal 6 to 7 and 7 to 8. Hands-On Led development and migration of mixmarket.org & themix.org. Created new intranet and subsites in Drupal 8. Created themes and custom modules. Developed several API integrations with Tableau, Salesforce, Totango, Mailchimp, etc. Managed the overall web systems architecture of MIX, which includes configuring, updating, troubleshooting, performance optimization and patching of several LAMP stack environments ranging from dev, stg, qa and load-balanced prod. Implemented Continuous Integration with Jenkins. Automation with Ansible. Performed code reviews and deployments.

Blackstone Technology Group, Arlington, VA Senior Technical Consultant

Oct 2011 - Oct 2014

Served as the Lead Engineer on the American Association of the Advancement of Science site's upgrade to Drupal and building content APIs for the organization. Served as lead developer on the FTC.gov site migration to Drupal, Healthdata.gov development and integration of Drupal with DKAN (external data repository). Served as lead developer on USBG.gov migration to Drupal. Developed new websites in Drupal. Utilized agile development methodologies. Configured and upgraded contributed modules from D6 to D7. Extended and built custom modules to meet site's requirements. Themed responsive mobile friendly sites. Used GIT versioning tool, Drush scripting, Acquia Cloud, Amazon EC2, Vagrant/Virtual boxes. Performed migration of sites (from static html & CMS) into Drupal. Implemented Workflows, SEO, Active Directory and Social media integrations. Optimized websites for high performance, increased usability and §508 compliance. Performed code reviews, technical writing and conducted client training.

EDUCATION:

BSc, Computer Systems, City University of New York, NY

Msc, University of District of Columbia, DC